sushmitamalakar.com 2018-08-09

# Privacy Policy - Sushmita Malakar Blog

**_If you require any more information or have any questions about the privacy policy, please feel free to contact us by email at sushmita.malakar@gmail.com._**  
**_  
_**

**_  
_****_  
_**At www.sushmitamalakar.com, the privacy of the visitors is of extreme importance. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information is received and collected by www.sushmitamalakar.com and how it is used.

Like many other websites, www.sushmitamalakar.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and the number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

This site is linked to various Google services like _Google AdSense_ and _Google Analytics.   _Therefore, www.sushmitamalakar.com collects various visitors' information like IP Addresses, clicks etc. This information is compliant with GDPR practices and this information will not be shared or misused by the website. You can read all the detailed policies [here](https://policies.google.com/).

In brief, these third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on www.sushmitamalakar.com send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see.  
**_  
_****_www.sushmitamalakar.com has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers._**

Whenever you leave a comment, the comment form asks for some of your information like name and email address. Your IP address is also tracked. All this is for the sole purpose of spam detection. Being a Google service again, the information collected through the comment form is never shared or misused.

There are no contact forms being used on this website. However, if you chose to contact www.sushmitamalakar.com using the email address provided, your information shared by you in the email will never be shared or used by the website.

The website uses external links and embedded contents (like video, images etc). These external sources might collect your data, use cookies and monitor your interaction with the embedded content.

Please be aware that the website is not responsible for the privacy practices of these external sources. It is encouraged that whenever you leave www.sushmitamalakar.com to visit these external links, please read their privacy policies separately.  You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. www.sushmitamalakar.com's privacy policy does not apply to, and cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or websites.

Some posts on these websites are sponsored and may contain affiliate links. Please treat these links as the external links as well. Rest assured, the sponsored posts are of the product and services which I have used personally and feel safe for the users of this website to try and test.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites.

The privacy policies might change with time and they will be updated here on this page.
